CHRISTINE BAGARINO

TOKYO-BASED PRODUCT MANAGER

▼ Tokyo, Japan |
▼ tokyopdm@gmail.com | in jp.linkedin.com/in/cbagarino

English and Japanese-speaking Product Manager with 7 years of experience developing for B2B, B2School, and B2C on web and mobile platforms. Well-versed in Agile, Scrum, Kanban, and Waterfall methodologies. Areas of expertise include:

- AI/ML Products
- Roadmapping
- Product Strategy
- Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- Software as a Service (SaaS)
- Product Lifecycle Management
- Design Sprint
- Metrics & Analytics
- Data Visualization

SKILLS & TOOLS

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT

PROGRAMMING & DATA

HTML/CSS
Python
SQL
Tableau

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

English
Japanese
French

CREATIVE SOFTWARE

Sketch InDesign
Photoshop Premiere Pro
Illustrator Affinity Publisher

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

STANFORD UNIVERSITY, CODE IN PLACE

April - May 2020 5-week online Python coding course, final project featured in The Stanford Daily (June 8, 2020)

GOOGLE LAUNCHPAD ACCELERATOR ALUMNA

October 2018 - February 2019 Google Japan, Tokyo

JAPANESE LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY TEST, N2

Issued December 2010

WASEDA UNIVERSITY, TOKYO

One year exchange, 2007-2008 School of International Liberal Studies (SILS)

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LONG BEACH

Graduated magna cum laude, 2010 Japanese, B.A. International Studies, B.A. Minor in Economics

WORK HISTORY

AUG 2018 - JUNE 2020

PRODUCT MANAGER

Joyz, Inc. - Tokyo, Japan

- Defined, prioritized, and executed the product roadmap for TerraTalk, an AI/ML based speech recognition app for English learning with 120,000+ users in K-12 schools and universities.
- Collaborated with researchers, developers, and designers to wireframe, prototype, design, build, and deploy features.
- Managed Build-Measure-Learn cycle to track continued success of features via product metrics and user data analysis.

Improved Requirements Handover Process

Improved development sprint velocity and reduced rework by implementing a standard framework for documentation, change management, and user acceptance scenarios with Gherkin testing.

Implemented OKRs

Introduced Objective-Key Result (OKR) framework at an organizational level; trained all VP-level and manager-level employees on best practices for implementing and cascading down OKRs.

Google Launchpad Accelerator Tokyo

As a member of the first cohort for Google's accelerator program for AI/ML startups in Japan, worked with Google engineers and mentors to identify key areas of improvement for product strategy and organizational growth.

APR 2013 - JUL 2018

DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEADER

Gaba Corporation – Tokyo, Japan

• As Academic Development team leader, managed learning product development for the top-rated *eikaiwa* school in Japan (based on 2018 Oricon Customer Rankings).

Collaborated with NTT Data on AI language learning tool

Conducted speech recognition data collection and developed proof of concept for an AI-based English level analysis tool using NTT corevo® voice recognition.

Developed SRS vocabulary learning app

As Product Owner, created requirements docs and wireframes for spaced-repetition (SRS) based vocabulary learning app.

JAN 2015 - PRESENT

WRITER, EDITOR, TRANSLATOR

Freelance - Tokyo, Japan

- Performs writing, editing, and translation services for clients including Gurunavi English and Brave Wave Productions.
- Notable contributions include editing for *Streets of Rage 4* album liner notes and official English lyrics translations on *Resurrection: Panzer Dragoon Saga 20th Anniversary Arrangement.*